Even in the seemingly endless
dark tunnels
there is light at the end.
Light in the darkness -
that's what cinema was for me.
In this simple
everything was possible for the shimmering square.
I felt that I was capable of anything.
But the world beyond cinema
was always hard and burdensome.
No elaborate plots
or touching words.
Life was lonely
and desolate.
And then someone appeared.
Kim Mubi.
I don't know if she's worried
the same darkness as me.
But most importantly...
I don't like the shimmering square anymore...
I love Kim Mubi.
If I tell a secret
will you still like me
Won't you leave me?
I think dad died because of me.
Sometimes you realize something only then,
when you say it out loud.
I thought I ran away from the past
but I was wrong.
Everything begins
from something insignificant and simple.
I was a child...
Mom, dad at home?
He sent you a gift
to the birthday
Open it.
…who wanted to be loved. That's all.
I didn't ask too much, did I?
- Whoever solves more wins!
- Okay.
Wait for me.
He could at least pretend better.
Dad, at the end of the movie…
- Are you director Kim Sung-hwan?
- Yes.
I am your big fan.
I didn't think I would meet you.
Can I shake your hand?
I also make movies.
- True? Thank you.
- Yes.
I really enjoyed your new movie.
How did you get to…
The child who was never loved...
I was amazed.
Are you here alone?
No. I came with my daughter.
…will live his whole life
with the thought that it is her fault.
Mubi!
But then I realized
that hating dad would be better.
So I hated him as much as I could.
It was not easy
hate that
who appeared only from time to time
and was kind to me.
But I wasn't going to back down.
Mubi, where's your dad?
I don't have a dad. He died.
I'm serious.
Mubi!
Mubi, is that your dad?
No, I don't know this man.
I wonder what little Mubi was like.
It was much more difficult with her than with me.
But I guess you get used to hating.
I wanted to see him less and less.
We were moving away...
and that suited me.
But...
I didn't want to see him like that.
FOUR-LEAF CLOVER
It was strange.
As if my insides were agitated.
Stop now at last!
No one will help you.
The director promised to help,
when we finish the project.
He spoke sincerely.
And you believed him again?
When you do that, I…
You can continue chasing movies.
Don't force yourself to be a father.
I don't care.
I will come tomorrow
for my little girl's birthday.
I'm not a child anymore.
I'm sorry I wasn't there
when you were little.
You have to come quickly, before you let
another rumor that your dad is dead.
I did so
because I thought you might show up
but not anymore.
I haven't thought for a long time
that I don't have a dad.
Mubi, I'm sorry.
- What should I do to fix everything?
- Are you serious?
Stop filming and come home.
can you
Hello.
Yes.
Mubi.
Dad had an accident.
I was cruel to him.
I thought he was pathetic
I was ashamed of him.
I knew it would hurt
and said it anyway.
I also suffered, so I thought
that I have the right to behave like that.
But I didn't want him to die.
Fair. I just…
I just wanted him to love me.
EPISODE 10
LIFE IS WONDERFUL AND AMAZING,
EVEN IF YOU'RE A JELLYFISH
I thought that when I confess
something incredible will happen.
But nothing happened. I'm so stupid.
It didn't happen.
And that's good.
It's strange, but I feel that way about you.
Everything is fine with me.
Then and in the future, be by my side, as now.
What are you thinking about?
About nothing.
About us
I'm thinking about us.
It's so beautiful here.
Shall we stay until dawn?
your mother will hate me
if you spend the night away from home.
Maybe it's a can
but I'm glad we went.
This tin can hear you.
Why do you drive such an old car?
Because it's cool.
Such cars are used in movies.
People love movies too much.
Why do you like movies?
I fell in love with cinema because I was afraid to be alone.
And later it was that
what I could do with Chun.
Gomme.
And what is your secret?
My secret?
Well…
He is dark.
He is difficult to bear, he is depressed.
And unpleasant.
I still want to hear.
When I was little, I was afraid to be alone.
I watched the video ad nauseum
until Chun came home.
It was hard to pretend to be happy all the time.
You were little. You could complain.
I was afraid that Chun would disappear then.
Even as a child it was clear to me
that Chun could disappear at any moment.
You were too kind, Goem.
I'm not good.
when i realized
that he tried to commit suicide
I pretended I didn't know anything.
I was silent until the end
because I thought it was because of me.
Gomme.
do you see
My secret...
depressed and cowardly.
One problem with us.
Truth?
I think death is…
lousy
Yes.
So it is.
What? Why is the door unlocked...
Congratulations
Greetings. Did you rest well yesterday?
You asked for a few days off. why are you here
There was nothing to do.
It doesn't look like you enjoyed your vacation.
What happened?
San Siku.
What?
What were we in your eyes?
When they were together with Chu A.
leave it I can't say.
You will sulk again. This is a forbidden topic.
Tell me.
are you serious
I only say because you ask
but you - that was something!
You walked around with a guitar on your back.
She was packing snacks
and ran after you with her tail.
In my opinion, Chu Ah was not your girlfriend.
She was like a mother to you. No.
More like a fan.
But she never got tired.
I will give her credit.
Really?
Well, just…
It seemed so from the side.
Do you know how you got on my nerves?
Only heard:
“Song Chu And this, Song Chu And that.
I will eat with Chu Ah. I will walk with Chu Ah.”
Except for the time you worked here
or over music
you literally did not leave that girl.
I even thought:
"How can a guy be like that?"
You were a great couple.
That's what I'm talking about.
This is possible only at this age.
Do you think you will ever love like this?
Or will you have such a relationship again?
I think you are very lucky to have met.
do you hear God is merciful.
I understood.
You saw Chu Ah yesterday, right?
I wanted to ask if we still have a chance...
but I don't know anymore.
Si Chun.
What makes love perfect?
Marriage?
Death in one day?
You are wrong.
Love is so perfect.
Is it clear to you?
If your love was great,
you should be happy
You know how many romantic movies there are
did i watch while running a video store?
I'm an expert on love.
That's why I have no rejection from women.
Finish cleaning. I wonder how the kitchen is there.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH
LET'S ALWAYS BE HAPPY
CHU A, IT'S ME, HONSI
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
THANK YOU FOR BEING IN MY LIFE
AND YOU STAY WITH ME, MY LOVE!
LOVE!
Good afternoon, ma'am.
what are you doing here
I was just about to call.
Mubi is still sleeping.
I know I came to you.
This is for you.
Flowers? Why suddenly?
Did you come to give me flowers?
Why all this?
I heard you like flowers.
Therefore, I took only the ones that are easier
grow as a gift…
are you crazy
What should I do about it? Who will plant them?
Sorry, I didn't know you were still here.
Didn't notice you among the flowers.
shut up
Yes, ma'am.
You understand what the neighbors will think
if Mubi will always be with you?
So maybe I'll be here all the time?
What do you think?
See you somewhere else.
Leave space between the flowers.
Can you show how it is done?
Probably not.
You can go home.
You said you think too much
but it's hard for you to talk about it.
Are you still like this?
I decided to change.
Good. Say whatever you want to say.
Something can only be completed in this way.
And if...
is there no one who should hear it?
They are here even if we can't see them.
I hoped
that Mubi will meet someone simpler,
but she met one just like herself.
I'm simple when with Mubi.
Then listen to what's on my girl's mind.
She has no one to lean on.
Really?
It seems to depend on you
more than you think.
I have to open a shop
so finish here.
Your mom likes me again!
why are you sitting here
He did a great job.
Isn't Golem cute?
Not a bit
But he's a good guy.
What kind of person was dad for you?
He was a miserable and stupid man.
I was unhappy longer than I was happy.
But some people in this world are just like that.
They lack talent
do what they love
and intelligence to know when to back off.
But if it wasn't for you
he would have given up much earlier.
He always wanted to show you
how well he could tell his story...
and that he never gives up.
That's a fool.
But you know...
you look more like dad
What? What are you talking about? I look like you.
You don't know how cute you are.
I see it in your movie.
You are as kind-hearted as your father.
So I want to see more of your movies.
Mom
You know…
I have something to say.
Mubi.
I'm sorry...
that was not kind to you.
At such moments I realize that I am still a child.
It wouldn't be so hard for you
if I were kinder to you
but I couldn't.
Not even close.
I'm sorry
I was too immersed in my pain
and did not see those who were nearby.
FROM A LOVING DAD
Am I not late?
I had to close the shop.
Did dad leave again?
What did you want to see? Let's see together.
I can see it myself.
You never go to the movies, mom.
Do you know who Batman is?
Of course. He's one of those guys
who fly in their underpants.
Not just one of those guys.
And you haven't seen the previous movies,
you will not understand anything.
I will understand when I look. Where? Come on.
Here.
Come on.
Why didn't I see that I was never alone
and there were always two of us?
Everything is fine.
It's okay, Mubi.
It's not your fault.
Don't you hate me?
How can I hate you?
Why am I so stupid?
sorry for complaining
that I was never loved.
I'm sorry for behaving like a child.
I'm sorry for what I perceived
your love for granted, mother.
I'm sorry that I didn't show you
more love
You gave everything to me.
I will try to be
the best mother for you.
You won't be hurt anymore.
You think we are with you
can we start living happily?
Yes.
Mom…
Why do you want to sell them to me?
They are very valuable.
- Something is not the same.
- They look like you.
Who is watching tapes now?
I don't even have a record player.
Consider it shelf decor.
- You are putting pressure on me.
- That's stupid.
You said to pay.
Almost crazy. Just pay for shipping.
I have to take them home
and pay you for shipping?
Don't be so smart and callous.
- What are you saying? forget it
- Wait!
You are so clumsy.
- What is it? Raise your leg.
- Why?
That's it.
Everything is fine. Climb up
Everything is fine. go Pay later.
I look funny.
It suits you. Go already.
When you pick it up, I'll sell it
the next party to his patron.
- Come on.
- Okay.
wait Why did you take it away?
You already have too much.
Well, you give.
Director Ma, where are you?
I asked you to come here quickly.
My God!
You scared me.
why are you here
How did you know where I live?
"Sorry, we can't
continue the project".
And that's all?
Do you just disappear? Are you out of your mind?
I thought about it a little more.
Indifferently.
I don't understand how you can give up
without even trying to find a solution.
Because you are always ready
take on another project?
Would you just dump everyone who was with you?
I didn't think you were like that.
You knew I didn't want to get involved
for this project, but insisted.
To be more precise,
you were ashamed to make a film.
Seriously?
You have to find a way out.
We can go to the production company.
No.
You're not going anywhere until you answer.
I wouldn't come
if it only applied to me.
But some put everything into this project.
You will have to step over me.
Are you lying on the ground?
That lousy Kim Mubi!
What did you call me?
You heard me. The film has been cancelled.
You are not my director.
I realized that you are annoying
as soon as we met
but you are even worse than I imagined.
You said I looked like a civil servant.
If only You look like a drunkard.
"The drunkard"? Who would have said!
What?
I'm going to find a solution.
Come with me or stay here.
Just now? Decision? Where are we going?
Director Kim, wait!
I didn't think we would meet again.
Did you come to talk about the contract?
I didn't think so either.
Perhaps the producers will contact you.
Then why are you here?
To say that she listened to music
which you sent yesterday
Music? What music?
It's just…
Did you send it to make me change my mind?
No.
Then why?
When I wrote this music…
i was happy
I don't remember the last time I felt this way.
It was a good feeling.
I took on this project,
to end everything with it.
This should have been a reason to leave that…
that I've been clinging to for far too long.
Everything ends anyway.
But the music made me feel something.
I was glad.
I sent this music
because I didn't think she belonged to me.
Then hold this thought a little longer.
you need
complete everything properly.
I'm not giving up yet
because music
the one you sent me is very beautiful.
Of course, there are other reasons
but i was listening to your music yesterday
and this is the very first reason.
So you will try to make a film?
You just have to figure out how.
Looking for an investor yourself
to protest near the production company
or cut the budget to a minimum.
I'll think of something.
Thank you in advance for your support.
So cool.
I just don't know if it's the music preference
above the script is good.
Director Kim!
Am I your director again?
Now you are my favorite director.
I'll ask just in case.
Do you sometimes not have much savings?
Just kidding.
You would see your faces. It's unpleasant.
think well
or drop the music after that.
OK.
I hope you don't.
I'm serious.
bye
I'll put a full stop after that.
You said you wouldn't be in a hurry.
You weren't talking about music.
No.
OK.
Looks like I've been holding on to the past for too long.
I think we're really going to part ways.
Yes.
And then...
let's not see each other again.
No matter what the excuse, nothing will work.
We will not be friends either.
When I hear about you, I'll pretend I didn't hear.
We will disappear…
from each other's lives.
But Chu Ah…
then we won't do any of it.
Fun conversations, silly jokes
and talk until we fall asleep.
This is what we do best.
Si Chun.
Can you live the rest of your life without it?
You will miss it very much.
Wake someone up just to talk.
Not everyone likes it.
How can I survive this?
It will pass.
Well…
If I hurt you...
We were good together.
We were very good together, Xi Chun.
Is it true?
You don't do it like that. look
It's like breathing.
Breathe naturally.
do you like
And you are an example to follow.
It's like you never
not caught smoking?
You don't know much about me, kid.
Chune
What?
do me a favor
Which one?
I still don't know much about you
so visit me in your dreams
from time to time
I won't get angry and I won't get it.
I will let you do whatever you want.
Why did you drink secretly?
I should have been called.
I want to have a drink with you too.
The same goes for smoking.
I'll smoke with you if you want.
So…
sometimes…
sometimes visit me in a dream.
Let's hang out.
What's funny?
I know
And it's funny to me.
Why are you crying, Goem?
Maybe you'll call me like you used to?
But you still won't come.
- Chune.
- What?
There's something I couldn't tell you.
Everything will be fine.
Everything will be fine with me.
Don't worry.
I lived a happy life because of you.
Therefore, I will try to live as best as possible.
You are so gloomy, not like yourself.
I was in a production company.
I promised to find an investor,
but how?
I don't know where to get the money.
What is it?
do you see I knew you wouldn't give up.
I watched my dad's movies again.
They are still ugly and boring.
But touching.
I don't know what he wanted to say.
So I plan to give it a try.
Maybe I'll find out later.
Well done.
But how do I do it?
if I don't have money?
Where can I find an investor?
I will sell all the tapes
and invest in your film.
I know how cheap they are.
Any help is important.
Why are you selling them?
I've watched enough movies.
I set myself a goal
watch all movies
But now I am more interested in the world.
It sounded a bit philosophical.
Cool, say?
Phew!
by the way
I will no longer be a film critic.
What?
I don't want to watch movies anymore.
Once we talked about it,
why didn't you write a review for my movie?
- I wrote.
- What?
When? Where? I didn't see it.
Do you want to see?
She is at home. Tell you?
No, thank you. I don't want to know.
- No, I will tell you.
- No, you don't have to.
- Listen.
- No need.
- First...
- Stop it.
When I first saw the movie…
- Wow...
- Stop it. I will be upset.
- I will tell only good things.
- Really?
Yes, only good.
In childhood
I wanted to become 20 years old overnight.
Just like in the movies.
Because childhood did not help
to overcome difficulties.
When I turned 20,
I quickly wanted to turn 30.
I thought I had to pass
stage of inexperience,
to become insensitive to pain.
But even when I turned 30
nothing has changed.
I just started to miss the moments,
that, as I once hoped, a quick minute.
Then I understood,
that every moment I live
continues my life.
Now I will live every moment to the fullest.
Because life is not a movie, but reality.
1 YEAR AND 6 MONTHS LATER
That's why I'm here.
I had to find a job.
And what was the question?
Mr. Co.
You applied knowing that
what does our company do?
Yes, this is a travel agency.
- You studied only at school.
- Yes.
But I think my level of experience
higher than others.
- Do you know foreign languages?
- No.
But I watched a lot
foreign films since I was little…
so, I guess I'll manage.
Chinese, English and…
Thank you
Yes.
I was on top. I'm going home already.
See you at home.
THE MOVIE "MELODY"
"MELODY", 2024
Kim Muba managed to make a movie.
And he failed.
No, I wouldn't say it's a failure.
How to explain?
Mubi made quite an artistic film,
which was very unlike her.
Thank you
But the strangest thing is that...
Finally, say something to your fans.
Perhaps persistence is my only strength.
…Hong Si Chun succeeded.
Thank you so much for your love and support.
It rarely happens that the soundtrack
more popular than the movie.
- I'm Hong Si Chun.
- Thank you.
But Xi Chun succeeded.
shall we go
Goodbye.
Well, you're a contagion.
And this, in your opinion, is successful,
but anonymous author?
You crave attention.
why are you here
Are you really not coming?
There will be a lot of meat,
and you have to fry it.
And don't get your hopes up, you fool.
Why? Through Chu Ah?
Do you want me to put
a partition between you?
Shut up. I can't because I have plans.
There are some troubles because of you.
Maybe you will be together again?
My hands are slippery.
I'm going Lock the door when you leave.
I'm dreaming
I won't come. I have to finish my work.
What? why don't you come
wait Are you still writing scripts?
Anyone else want them?
disappear I'm writing even more this time.
Maybe you're avoiding your ex too?
What are you talking about? I really have a job.
Can I invite Hounshee?
Be impartial
and don't invite any of us, okay?
He still wouldn't come.
He is very busy.
And how do you feel about your ex?
succeeded? Are you jealous?
Yes, I'm jealous. bye
Chu A was jealous,
because her story was overshadowed by music.
Life is sometimes surprising.
Oh yes.
And I have someone who bores me at home.
Gomm!
Why so long? We have a lot of work to do.
take it
Not a neighbor, but rather a dependent student.
I let him move in,
because I had a spare room,
but now I regret it.
You have already done everything.
Goem, you know
how hard was it to do everything yourself?
We already are.
How is the interview?
Perfectly.
I think I will get a job.
You study in the evenings.
Why are you torturing yourself?
I know I am a diligent guy.
Mubi forcing?
- No, I...
- Yes.
No.
Yes!
When did I force you?
This is your life. Do whatever you want.
I took fresh meat.
If you need someone
who will replace you in the butcher shop,
what do you think of my candidacy?
- Find a job.
- Yes.
And something important.
I ask for your attention.
The investor came.
The premiere of the movie Mubi took place by a miracle
thanks to the rich director,
who had nothing to do.
I am very glad to see you.
What is the matter with him?
I'm here to celebrate
the success of director Kim…
He suddenly announced that he was a producer
which supports the dreams of young directors.
He starts everything over and in his own way.
Let me share the joy with you.
- Do you know how to fry meat?
- Me?
- Jung Hoo, let's go.
- Good.
- I need to wash the salad.
- Salad.
Mr. Ma, hold on.
- The culprit is the holiday!
- Thank you.
Please.
Cheers.
Thank you. Congratulations.
- Good.
- True?
Very good.
The meat is excellent.
Deliciously.
"MELODY"
LIMITED QUANTITY
THE MOST CHARMING MELODY OF THE SUMMER
I knew I could spot talent.
Hello.
DIRECTOR KIM MUBY
Ko Geum is not watching movies now.
But sometimes he goes with me to the shooting
the field is boring as it is now.
According to him, Kim Mubi -
this is the only film in his life.
what are you doing
This is my storyboard.
Mubi, when the main character cries,
make a general plan instead of a macro plan...
I asked not to interfere in my work.
Your previous work was excellent,
but you should be more sensitive...
- Are you looking for death?
- What?
What are you, a film critic?
When I'm with Gyom, we still switch genres.
Sometimes it is a tearful drama.
Sometimes a touching family film.
And sometimes a completely pointless action movie.
I'm just expressing my humble opinion
as one of the spectators.
What are you talking about? Give it back!
Wait!
Hello,
girl pretending to be evil
but actually very good.
But the best of them…
melodrama.
LIKE IN THE MOVIE
Translation of subtitles: Natalya Kovalyshyn